At least you can
help us save 10 people from insurance fraud.
Our reason is to create
transparency in this complex world
of insurance.  So in this video today I'm going to
decode my personal five
best [music] health insurance companies.  Yes
my dear the most unique thing that this health
insurance company has [music] is
that you have flexibility at the
time of discharge that you have zero waiting
period.  Now last but not the least is my
health insurance which
is covered by my health insurance and that is Hello Everyone
Welcome to Transforming 360.  You must have
tried many times to find out
which are the three or five best health
insurance companies so that you
can take the right decision and get a direction to
buy the ultimate health insurance [music] for your future.  So
in this video today I'm going to decode
my personal five best [music] health
insurance companies.  Yes my dear, do not
skip the video at all.  This video is going to be
very useful for you today.   If you have
not subscribed to the channel yet, then
please subscribe to the channel.  Please
share this video with as many people as possible.
Because you can help us save at least 10 people from
insurance fraud.
Our reason is
to create transparency in this
complex world of these.  Hi am
myself Dheeraj Mahajan The Founder of
Transforming 360 More than 12 years of
Health Insurance [Music] experience including 11
years of my job journey where I have
developed almost two states.
Developed 140 plus managers.
Trained over 5,000 advisors and
experienced over 16,000 games
[music].  With this rich experience,
today I am going to decode for you the five best
real time health insurance
companies [music]
and the logic behind it.  But it is not necessary
that those five best health [music]
insurance companies are suitable for you.
Because ultimately health insurance is all
about the medical eligibility.  But still, it
is important for you to know these [music] things so that
when you are making your decision, you should
not forget to consider them.
At least you should definitely try one of these five
[music] companies for yourself.
But one more thing you have to keep in mind is
how any health insurance company becomes the best [music].  For this I will
give you two important tips at the end of the video.
So let's start the video and
understand which are my five favorite health
insurance companies.  So let's start the
video and understand the first thing about
health insurance.  So the first health
insurance I would like to mention is from public
sector unit companies.  I mean,
among the PSU [music] health insurance companies, my favorite health insurance company is
No India.  Yes my dear because No
India is serving [music] in India with a huge legacy.
Earlier it used to be an
insurance company of T Group.
Ultimately later it merged and became a PSU unit
and the best thing that is there in New India is that the
system communication is very
ethically transparent.  If
you talk about ICR or claim settlement
ratio then this company is a much better
option.  But features and terms and conditions should
never be ignored.  So the
flexibility of coverage is
somewhat restricted in New India.
But if you are a PSU lover, if
you need the government's backup, if
you feel that no, I
prefer to go only with public companies
[Music] then the first preference you should give should be to
New India.  Let's move ahead and
see what the other health insurance
company is.  So the second health
insurance company is Bajaj General Insurance
Company.  Earlier it was Bajaj Allianz.  So
Bajaj belongs to India and Allianz
is a foreign backup which
has a very strong presence across the globe
[music]
and Allianz's backup
operated in more than 100 countries.  If we talk about it,
this company [Music] has the best solvency margin.  The claim
experience of people has been amazing.  But there is
only one problem here [with music]
and that is pricing.  Pricing
is too much at high ranges.  Even if
we talk about middle age people and want to look at high sum insured, then
Bajaj General Insurance
is a very good option for those people who have
pockets, that is, those who do
not want any compromise on quality and they will
not compromise on the sum insured also.
But ultimately I would like to buy it at the right price.  If they
get quality at any price, then they want to move towards that, so there is
not going to be a better option for you than Bajaj Aya and later I will
also tell you about my personal health insurance company from
where I am getting my health insurance, so now let's move
towards the third health insurance, the third health insurance company is
HDFC Ergo General Insurance.  HDFCO is one of
the finest health insurance companies.
Because of the flexibility of communication
and the systems of claim settlement.  These are very
amazing systems.  There are amazing
products and the
customers have a great experience [music].  But
ultimately we have to see for whom the right fitment
is made.  So just like Bajaj
is for a very high end clientele [music], HDFC Ergo
is also a right fit for a high end clientele.  Because
you have to look for life long renewal.  Because
today you have medical eligibility.  You can
choose any company.  Because at lower ages the
premium is almost head to head.  But you should
always look at the long term premium which is
your renewal.  And HDFC is a quality
brand so it keeps increasing its prices over the time.
So
ultimately, if in the future [music]
your medical eligibility gets impaired, meaning you
develop a new medical problem,
you will not be able to vote in any other company.
That's why health insurance [music] is not a short-
term decision.  If your pocket is
not very strong, or
your minimum annual income is not Rs 50 lakh, then I will
not recommend HDFC to you at all.
But if your income is Rs 50 lakh and above
and you can bear the increment of long term pay premium [Music]
then you should not
miss HDFCRO at any cost.  Let us move ahead
and know about the fourth health
insurance company which comes under one of the best
health insurance companies and
that company is ICICI LBRD.  ICICI LBRD is a
company that has given great leaders to the entire [music] insurance
industry.  There have been
many big innovations and this
company has given systems, that is, all the automation
to India [music].
This insurance company comes with great clarity when it comes to the claims process.
[MUSIC] If the claim is rejected, it's rejected.  If it
is accepted then it means it is accepted.   There
is no other if and but the quality of
services is truly amazing.  Communication
is truly amazing.  Earlier this health
insurance company used to be very expensive.
Meaning that this was the category of company between Bajaj Ali and HDFC Ago.
But over the
period of time ICC LB has changed its strategies
and today
introduced itself as a middle man
[Music] which is Star Health Insurance
Care Health Insurance or any other company
[Music] you can compare the premium very easily.
But there was a problem
in ICICI Lombard [Music] which was
a hidden term and condition of material change and
we challenged that hidden term and condition
last March i.e. on 8th March 2025
that this term and condition like material change
is very dangerous for the customer.
Meaning that the condition meant that it is the responsibility of the client
that at the
time of renewal in future, if any medical
challenges arise, any changes occur,
any new medical history develops, then
it has to be informed to the insurance company and the company
will decide the scope of cover and end
premium.  This means that the company has the right that
if in future I, as a customer,
develop cancer, then I have a health insurance of Rs 1 crore or Rs 2
crore.   The
company can reduce it and
also increase the end premium,
which was a very dangerous hidden term and
condition which we challenged.
After much persistent communication the company finally
gave a [musical] justification and
gave credit to the Bishop.  You must have
seen the video.  If you haven't seen it, then definitely go to the channel and
watch it.  And till now there
is still no clarity on the condition whether it has been removed
or not.  So
you should not miss this part here at all.  OtherWise
Company is truly amazing.  The most unique thing about
this health insurance company is the
flexibility you have
at the time of discharge.  You have zero
waiting period.  If your sum insured is Rs
15 lakh or more.
If your health insurance cover is more than Rs 15 lakh,
then you do
not need to wait at the time of discharge.  Your
discharge is already approved.  Now last
but not the least is my health insurance
which covers my health insurance and
that is Tata AIG.  As soon as we hear the name Tata,
reliability comes to our mind.  But along with this,
it is very important to see
in insurance that term and condition features are
not everything, my dear, when I
identified my health insurance for myself
[music], the first
priority I gave was to term and condition.
I found it best to choose a health insurance company where there is
better transparency of terms and conditions.  So if we compare all the five companies, then
if we
look at two parameters, the most important one is transparency of terms and conditions
and the second one is [music]
flexibility.  So health insurance is all about
term and condition and not health
insurance my dear whether it is your term
insurance, financial disability
insurance, home insurance, any
kind of insurance [music],
insurance is totally based on your term
and condition and not on features, features are like
getting double honey free with Dabur Chammanpan Praj and over that
period of time some things get removed and
[music] you get a shock.  So
ultimately the terms and conditions should not be missed.
Let's take
a reality check of these five health insurance companies [Music].
So if we talk about the term and condition which
is the most important factor, then
among the five companies, if you talk about
ICICI LBD, if you talk about Bajaj Ali,
if you talk about HDFC Ergo or if you
talk about Tata EIG or New India
Insurance, then the most
transparent and the minimum policy
wording if anyone has it, then it is Tata
[Music] EIG's Miggar Premier which
makes this policy the best, secondly,
if we talk about your flexibility, flexibility of underwriting, then
you will get the maximum flexibility of underwriting.
Meaning, if you have a lot of
medical history, which
company will accept you.  So, among these five,
if there is any underwriting which is most flexible,
where any kind of
medical history i.e. within a limit, then
you will get the maximum in New India.
Secondly, you will get flexibility
within Bajaj.  Thirdly, you will
find flexibility inside the HDFC [Music] Ergo.  Fourth, you will get
this flexibility in your ICICI LB and lastly,
in Tata, Tata
issues your policy after a lot of scrutiny.  But once it is
issued in these five health insurance
companies [music] you will never have to face any claim
rejection.
Except for two things.  If you have committed any fraud or
misled someone while taking the policy, then
definitely no insurance company will
give you any claim.  The second thing is that if you get a
claim for permanent exclusion, that is
[music] diseases which are never
covered or some such conditions for which
claim is never received, these are called
permanent exclusions.  Now,
whichever health insurance you find your favourite among these five,
ensure that you do
not face any claim rejection in the future.  So for that,
two tips that I told you in the beginning.  The
first important tip is to
hire the right consultancy.  This means
hiring the right intermediary so that
in the future it can automatically solve all those problems
at the time of buying the policy.
Because most of the biggest mistakes happen at the time of taking the policy.
Wrong expectations are
created and reality is something else.
So definitely [music] the first thing you have to do is
identify a professional and ethical insurance intermediary.  And the
second most important thing is declaration.
You have to give the complete medical declaration
and also understand
what are the permanent exclusions [music]
so that the future does not become a shock for you.  I am
giving you one more additional tip that as
our current Finance Minister has also
highlighted that you do
not have to take insurance from the bank.  The most
misleading [music] and misselling is happening
in banks.  So please avoid banks and
also avoid online platforms.
You have to try to avoid those people yourself.   It is
very important for you to understand self-responsibility
that you are the victim yourself and
in future after wasting a lot of your money, you can
challenge your claim rejection in that bad situation
and ultimately you can travel.
We would never want this to happen.  These were the five best
health insurance companies in my opinion.
You might think something else [music].
If you are intermediate then your opinion may be
something else.  Every person has a
different way of making comparisons.  The video I have
shared is based on my experience only.
Because many viewers
asked me this thing, so I told you this thing as a self
responsibility [music].
Your approach may be
that you need cheap health insurance.
So you have other options.  [Music] If
you have the option or not, then I want to see
according to my network, that is, according to my city,
which networks have more
hospitals [Music], then
you can decide accordingly.
My opinion was I told you the five best
[music] health insurance.  But it is
not that other health insurance
companies are bad.  She is also doing good work.
But I bet you don't miss the two
tips I've given you.   The
first [music] is that you have to get it through the right intermediate.  The
second thing to do is declare everything
and as a customer you have to make yourself
aware of what you don't get rather than what you get.
I hope this video is going to be
very useful for you.  If you liked the video,
please give your blessings by commenting in the comment section, share it
, like it and help this
video grow.  Because our vision is
to create transparency in this
complex world of insurance.  This
world is definitely very complex but it
is also very supportive [music].  Because
in the last financial year, the health
insurance company has
settled claims worth Rs 99,000 crore [music].  Almost 75
million people have been saved from ruin.
This industry is very useful.  But
ultimately [music]
we have been rejected for health insurance for more than 50 lakh people.
Whose total amount was Rs
29,9933 crore.  So the purpose of this video is
just to create awareness.  It's not
[MUSIC] that these five West Health
Insurance Company claims haven't been rejected.
Hue Mi Dear But [Music]
Ultimately the reasons have been the same two, non-
disclosure [Music] or secondly, I do
n't know the terms of my policy.  Waiting
periods are not mentioned.  And
thirdly, I took it from the wrong platform and did
not get any support at the time of support.
See you very soon with new videos.
[Music] What topic do you want the next video to be about
?  Please give your opinion by commenting in the comment section.
I wish you and your
below family, have a prosperous and a
wonderful journey of life.